<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jane Austen Core</title>
	<atom:link href="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore</link>
	<description>The Vintage Library</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 01:50:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/cropped-6538dbc9-22f4-47e1-b42e-f73d66293da8-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Jane Austen Core</title>
	<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Emma Movie</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma-movie/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma-movie/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 16:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Movie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Emma (stylized as Emma.) is a 2020 period romantic comedy film directed by Autumn de Wilde, from a screenplay by Eleanor Catton, based on Jane Austen&#8217;s 1815 novel of the same name. It stars Anya Taylor-Joy as Miss Emma Woodhouse, a wealthy and elegant young woman living with her father in Regency-era England who amuses herself with matchmaking and meddles in the romantic lives of those closest to her. The film also stars Johnny Flynn, Josh O&#8217;Connor, Callum Turner, Mia Goth, Miranda Hart, and Bill Nighy. Produced by Perfect World Pictures, Working Title Films and Blueprint Pictures, a film adaptation of Austen&#8217;s novel by Focus Features began development in October 2018 when Taylor-Joy was cast in the title role, with de Wilde attached as the director. The remainder of the supporting roles were cast by March 2019. Principal photography took place between March and June 2019 across England. Emma was released in the United Kingdom on 14 February 2020, and in the United States on 21 February 2020 by Universal Pictures. It received generally favourable reviews, with the performances and production design singled out for praise. It grossed $26.5 million worldwide against its budget of $10 million. The film received two Academy Award nominations for Best Costume Design and Best Makeup and Hairstyling at the 93rd Academy Awards, as well as a Best Costume Design nomination at the 74th British Academy Film Awards, three nominations at the 26th Critics&#8217; Choice Awards, and a Golden Globe Award for Best Actress – Motion Picture Comedy or Musical nomination (for Taylor-Joy) at the 78th Golden Globe Awards. Miss Taylor&#8217;s wedding to Mr Weston is a sad day for Mr Woodhouse, but they go to church nonetheless. Emma has orchestrated the match. After the wedding party with Miss and Mrs Bates, Mr Knightly shows up. Mr Frank Churchill, Mr Weston&#8217;s son &#8211; does not. Miss Harriet Smith comes to visit and becomes Emma&#8217;s new friend. Emma starts making a match for Harriet and Mr Elton, the vicar. Harriet looks to Emma for everything. Harriet is in love with Mr Robert Martin &#8211; a farmer, but Emma persuades her to refuse him. They spend more time with Mr Elton and Emma paints Harriet&#8217;s picture. Mr Elton frames it in a cabinet. Winter brings Isabella and John Knightly, Emma&#8217;s sister and Knightly&#8217;s brother, with their 5 children. Harriet is sick over Christmas. The Knightly&#8217;s, the Woodhouses and Mr Elton go to the Weston&#8217;s for a dinner party, but as it starts to snow, they leave early. Emma is with Mr Elton, who confesses his love for her. She informs him she has no plans of matrimony. Emma must tell Harriet and she nearly throws the picture and its frame into the fire, but Emma keeps it. As Isabella leaves, Jane Fairfax &#8211; Miss Bates&#8217; niece, has come to stay. Frank and Jane were at Weymouth in October &#8211; the same month as Mr Weston&#8217;s weather. Emma plays an old English folk tune with sheet music and Jane plays Mozart&#8217;s sonata in F without. Harriet has an awkward encounter with the Martins. Frank Churchill has returned. They have a ball, where Jane and Knightly duet to &#8216;Drink to me only with thine eyes&#8217;. Emma returns to church to find her pew has been taken by Mrs Agusta Elton. There is a public ball, where Mr Elton does not dance with miss Smith, but Knightly does. Knightly loves Emma and is about to profess it when Frank comes in with Harriet who has been attacked by gypsies. After a visit to Donwell, they go to Box Hill, where Emma insults Miss Bates. After being scolded by Mr Knightly, Emma apologises. Frank Churchill is engaged to Jane Fairfax. Harriet is in love with Knightly, but thinks Emma loves him, so they break off their friendship. Emma apologises to Mr Martin and Harriet is engaged to him. Her father is a tradesman from Bristol. Mr Knightly and Emma get married .]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Emma</strong></em> (stylized as <em><strong>Emma.</strong></em>) is a 2020 period romantic comedy film directed by Autumn de Wilde, from a screenplay by Eleanor Catton, based on Jane Austen&#8217;s 1815 novel of the same name. It stars Anya Taylor-Joy as Miss Emma Woodhouse, a wealthy and elegant young woman living with her father in Regency-era England who amuses herself with matchmaking and meddles in the romantic lives of those closest to her. The film also stars Johnny Flynn, Josh O&#8217;Connor, Callum Turner, Mia Goth, Miranda Hart, and Bill Nighy.</p>



<p>Produced by Perfect World Pictures, Working Title Films and Blueprint Pictures, a film adaptation of Austen&#8217;s novel by Focus Features began development in October 2018 when Taylor-Joy was cast in the title role, with de Wilde attached as the director. The remainder of the supporting roles were cast by March 2019. Principal photography took place between March and June 2019 across England.</p>



<p><em>Emma</em> was released in the United Kingdom on 14 February 2020, and in the United States on 21 February 2020 by Universal Pictures. It received generally favourable reviews, with the performances and production design singled out for praise. It grossed $26.5 million worldwide against its budget of $10 million. The film received two Academy Award nominations for Best Costume Design and Best Makeup and Hairstyling at the 93rd Academy Awards, as well as a Best Costume Design nomination at the 74th British Academy Film Awards, three nominations at the 26th Critics&#8217; Choice Awards, and a Golden Globe Award for Best Actress – Motion Picture Comedy or Musical nomination (for Taylor-Joy) at the 78th Golden Globe Awards.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="675" height="1000" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma_-2_6.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma_-2_6.jpg 675w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma_-2_6-203x300.jpg 203w" sizes="(max-width: 675px) 100vw, 675px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">source: pinterest</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Miss Taylor&#8217;s wedding to Mr Weston is a sad day for Mr Woodhouse, but they go to church nonetheless. Emma has orchestrated the match. After the wedding party with Miss and Mrs Bates, Mr Knightly shows up. Mr Frank Churchill, Mr Weston&#8217;s son &#8211; does not. Miss Harriet Smith comes to visit and becomes Emma&#8217;s new friend. Emma starts making a match for Harriet and Mr Elton, the vicar. Harriet looks to Emma for everything. Harriet is in love with Mr Robert Martin &#8211; a farmer, but Emma persuades her to refuse him. They spend more time with Mr Elton and Emma paints Harriet&#8217;s picture. Mr Elton frames it in a cabinet. Winter brings Isabella and John Knightly, Emma&#8217;s sister and Knightly&#8217;s brother, with their 5 children. Harriet is sick over Christmas. The Knightly&#8217;s, the Woodhouses and Mr Elton go to the Weston&#8217;s for a dinner party, but as it starts to snow, they leave early. Emma is with Mr Elton, who confesses his love for her. She informs him she has no plans of matrimony. Emma must tell Harriet and she nearly throws the picture and its frame into the fire, but Emma keeps it. As Isabella leaves, Jane Fairfax &#8211; Miss Bates&#8217; niece, has come to stay. Frank and Jane were at Weymouth in October &#8211; the same month as Mr Weston&#8217;s weather. Emma plays an old English folk tune with sheet music and Jane plays Mozart&#8217;s sonata in F without. Harriet has an awkward encounter with the Martins. Frank Churchill has returned. They have a ball, where Jane and Knightly duet to &#8216;Drink to me only with thine eyes&#8217;. Emma returns to church to find her pew has been taken by Mrs Agusta Elton. There is a public ball, where Mr Elton does not dance with miss Smith, but Knightly does. Knightly loves Emma and is about to profess it when Frank comes in with Harriet who has been attacked by gypsies. After a visit to Donwell, they go to Box Hill, where Emma insults Miss Bates. After being scolded by Mr Knightly, Emma apologises. Frank Churchill is engaged to Jane Fairfax. Harriet is in love with Knightly, but thinks Emma loves him, so they break off their friendship. Emma apologises to Mr Martin and Harriet is engaged to him. Her father is a tradesman from Bristol. Mr Knightly and Emma get married .</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pride &#038; Prejudice Movie</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-prejudice-movie/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-prejudice-movie/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 16:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Movie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=93</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pride &#38; Prejudice is a 2005 romantic drama film directed by Joe Wright, in his feature directorial debut, and based on Jane Austen&#8217;s 1813 novel of the same name. The film features five sisters from an English family of landed gentry as they deal with issues of marriage, morality and misconceptions. Keira Knightley stars in the lead role of Elizabeth Bennet, while Matthew Macfadyen plays her romantic interest Mr. Darcy. The glorious world of Jane Austen is at last brought back to the big screen in all its romance, wit, and emotional force in&#160;Pride &#38; Prejudice. Faithful to the setting and period of the beloved novel and filmed entirely on location in the U.K., this is the first movie version of the story in 65 years. The classic tale of love and misunderstanding unfolds in class-conscious England near the close of the 18th century. The five Bennet sisters – Elizabeth, or Lizzie (Keira Knightley), Jane (Rosamund Pike), Lydia (Jena Malone), Mary (Talulah Riley), and Kitty (Carey Mulligan) – have been raised well aware of their mother&#8217;s (two-time Academy Award nominee Brenda Blethyn) fixation on finding them husbands and securing set futures. The spirited and intelligent Elizabeth, however, strives to live her life with a broader perspective, as encouraged by her doting father (two-time Golden Globe Award winner Donald Sutherland). When wealthy bachelor Mr. Bingley (Simon Woods) takes up residence in a nearby mansion, the Bennets are abuzz. Amongst the man&#8217;s sophisticated circle of London friends and the influx of young militia officers, surely there will be no shortage of suitors for the Bennet sisters. Eldest daughter Jane, serene and beautiful, seems poised to win Mr. Bingley&#8217;s heart. For her part, Lizzie meets with the handsome and &#8211; it would seem &#8211; snobbish Mr. Darcy (Matthew Macfadyen), and the battle of the sexes is joined. Their encounters are frequent and spirited yet far from encouraging. Lizzie finds herself even less inclined to accept a marriage proposal from a distant cousin, Mr. Collins (Tom Hollander), and – supported by her father – stuns her mother and Mr. Collins by declining. When the heretofore good-natured Mr. Bingley abruptly departs for London, devastating Jane, Lizzie holds Mr. Darcy culpable for contributing to the heartbreak. But a crisis involving youngest sister Lydia soon opens Lizzie&#8217;s eyes to the true nature of her relationship with Mr. Darcy. The ensuing rush of feelings leaves no one unchanged, and inspires the Bennets and everyone around them to reaffirm what is most important in life. Take a look at the trailer for&#160;Pride &#38; Prejudice&#160;here https://youtu.be/1dYv5u6v55Y]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Pride &amp; Prejudice</strong></em> is a 2005 romantic drama film directed by Joe Wright, in his feature directorial debut, and based on Jane Austen&#8217;s 1813 novel of the same name. The film features five sisters from an English family of landed gentry as they deal with issues of marriage, morality and misconceptions. Keira Knightley stars in the lead role of Elizabeth Bennet, while Matthew Macfadyen plays her romantic interest Mr. Darcy.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="691" height="1024" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/download-4-691x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-94" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/download-4-691x1024.jpg 691w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/download-4-202x300.jpg 202w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/download-4.jpg 736w" sizes="(max-width: 691px) 100vw, 691px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">source: pinterest</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The glorious world of Jane Austen is at last brought back to the big screen in all its romance, wit, and emotional force in&nbsp;<strong><em>Pride &amp; Prejudice</em></strong>. Faithful to the setting and period of the beloved novel and filmed entirely on location in the U.K., this is the first movie version of the story in 65 years.</p>



<p>The classic tale of love and misunderstanding unfolds in class-conscious England near the close of the 18th century. The five Bennet sisters – Elizabeth, or Lizzie (Keira Knightley), Jane (Rosamund Pike), Lydia (Jena Malone), Mary (Talulah Riley), and Kitty (Carey Mulligan) – have been raised well aware of their mother&#8217;s (two-time Academy Award nominee Brenda Blethyn) fixation on finding them husbands and securing set futures. The spirited and intelligent Elizabeth, however, strives to live her life with a broader perspective, as encouraged by her doting father (two-time Golden Globe Award winner Donald Sutherland).</p>



<p>When wealthy bachelor Mr. Bingley (Simon Woods) takes up residence in a nearby mansion, the Bennets are abuzz. Amongst the man&#8217;s sophisticated circle of London friends and the influx of young militia officers, surely there will be no shortage of suitors for the Bennet sisters. Eldest daughter Jane, serene and beautiful, seems poised to win Mr. Bingley&#8217;s heart. For her part, Lizzie meets with the handsome and &#8211; it would seem &#8211; snobbish Mr. Darcy (Matthew Macfadyen), and the battle of the sexes is joined.</p>



<p>Their encounters are frequent and spirited yet far from encouraging. Lizzie finds herself even less inclined to accept a marriage proposal from a distant cousin, Mr. Collins (Tom Hollander), and – supported by her father – stuns her mother and Mr. Collins by declining. When the heretofore good-natured Mr. Bingley abruptly departs for London, devastating Jane, Lizzie holds Mr. Darcy culpable for contributing to the heartbreak. But a crisis involving youngest sister Lydia soon opens Lizzie&#8217;s eyes to the true nature of her relationship with Mr. Darcy.</p>



<p>The ensuing rush of feelings leaves no one unchanged, and inspires the Bennets and everyone around them to reaffirm what is most important in life.</p>



<p>Take a look at the trailer for&nbsp;<em>Pride &amp; Prejudice</em>&nbsp;here <a href="https://youtu.be/1dYv5u6v55Y">https://youtu.be/1dYv5u6v55Y</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-prejudice-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Persuasion Movie</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion-movie/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion-movie/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 16:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Movie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=89</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Persuasion&#160;is a 2022 American&#160;romantic drama&#160;film directed by&#160;Carrie Cracknell&#160;from a screenplay by&#160;Ron Bass&#160;and Alice Victoria Winslow, based on the&#160;novel of the same name&#160;by&#160;Jane Austen. The film stars&#160;Dakota Johnson,&#160;Cosmo Jarvis,&#160;Nikki Amuka-Bird,&#160;Mia McKenna-Bruce,&#160;Richard E. Grant, and&#160;Henry Golding. Persuasion&#160;was released in the United States on July 8, 2022, before its streaming release on July 15, 2022, by&#160;Netflix. The film received generally negative reviews criticizing the film&#8217;s modernization of the source material and the main protagonist Anne Elliott&#160;breaking the fourth wall&#160;by interacting with the audience. Persuasion&#160;tells the story of Anne Elliot, a young woman who is considered past her prime. (She’s 26 or 27.) She had a great love once when she was younger, but her family convinced her to give him up. Now, it’s years later and that love, Captain Frederick Wentworth, is back in town and visiting with people she knows. Their first meeting is… awkward to say the least. But they are continually put together and a friendship starts to form and from there, they realize the spark they had when they were in love all those years ago is still there. But it wouldn’t be a Jane Austen romance if there weren’t at least a few obstacles in the way. And some of those obstacles might just be Anne and Frederick themselves. It’s hard to say “Hey, I still like you. Do you still like me?” after eight years. Take a look at the trailer for&#160;Persuasion&#160;here: https://youtu.be/Fz7HmgPJQak]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Persuasion</strong></em>&nbsp;is a 2022 American&nbsp;romantic drama&nbsp;film directed by&nbsp;Carrie Cracknell&nbsp;from a screenplay by&nbsp;Ron Bass&nbsp;and Alice Victoria Winslow, based on the&nbsp;novel of the same name&nbsp;by&nbsp;Jane Austen. The film stars&nbsp;Dakota Johnson,&nbsp;Cosmo Jarvis,&nbsp;Nikki Amuka-Bird,&nbsp;Mia McKenna-Bruce,&nbsp;Richard E. Grant, and&nbsp;Henry Golding.</p>



<p><em>Persuasion</em>&nbsp;was released in the United States on July 8, 2022, before its streaming release on July 15, 2022, by&nbsp;Netflix. The film received generally negative reviews criticizing the film&#8217;s modernization of the source material and the main protagonist Anne Elliott&nbsp;breaking the fourth wall&nbsp;by interacting with the audience.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="320" height="400" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/PERSUASION-2022-Trailer-Featurette-Images-and-Posters.png" alt="" class="wp-image-90" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/PERSUASION-2022-Trailer-Featurette-Images-and-Posters.png 320w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/PERSUASION-2022-Trailer-Featurette-Images-and-Posters-240x300.png 240w" sizes="(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">source: pinterest</figcaption></figure></div>


<p><em>Persuasion</em>&nbsp;tells the story of Anne Elliot, a young woman who is considered past her prime. (She’s 26 or 27.) She had a great love once when she was younger, but her family convinced her to give him up. Now, it’s years later and that love, Captain Frederick Wentworth, is back in town and visiting with people she knows.</p>



<p>Their first meeting is… awkward to say the least. But they are continually put together and a friendship starts to form and from there, they realize the spark they had when they were in love all those years ago is still there.</p>



<p>But it wouldn’t be a Jane Austen romance if there weren’t at least a few obstacles in the way. And some of those obstacles might just be Anne and Frederick themselves. It’s hard to say “Hey, I still like you. Do you still like me?” after eight years.</p>



<p>Take a look at the trailer for&nbsp;<em>Persuasion</em>&nbsp;here: <a href="https://youtu.be/Fz7HmgPJQak">https://youtu.be/Fz7HmgPJQak</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Persuasion</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Novel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=84</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Persuasion&#160;is the last novel completed by&#160;Jane Austen. It was published on December 20, 1817, along with&#160;Northanger Abbey, six months after her death, although the title page is dated 1818. The story concerns Anne Elliot, an Englishwoman of 27 years, whose family moves to lower their expenses and reduce their debt by renting their home to an Admiral and his wife. The wife&#8217;s brother, Captain Frederick Wentworth, was engaged to Anne in 1806, but the engagement was broken when Anne was persuaded by her friends and family to end their relationship. Anne and Captain Wentworth, both single and unattached, meet again after a seven-year separation, setting the scene for many humorous encounters as well as a second, well-considered chance at love and marriage for Anne. The novel was well-received in the early 19th century, but its greater fame came later in the century and continued into the 20th and 21st centuries. Much scholarly debate on Austen&#8217;s work has since been published. Anne Elliot is noteworthy among Austen&#8217;s heroines for her relative maturity. As&#160;Persuasion&#160;was Austen&#8217;s last completed work, it is accepted as her most maturely written novel, showing a refinement of literary conception indicative of a woman approaching 40 years of age. Her use of&#160;free indirect speech&#160;in narrative was in full evidence by 1816. Persuasion&#160;has been the subject of several adaptations, including four made-for-television adaptations, theatre productions, radio broadcasts, and other literary works.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Persuasion</strong></em>&nbsp;is the last novel completed by&nbsp;Jane Austen. It was published on December 20, 1817, along with&nbsp;<em>Northanger Abbey</em>, six months after her death, although the title page is dated 1818.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="353" height="561" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Persuasion-Barnes-Noble-Collectible-Editions.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-85" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Persuasion-Barnes-Noble-Collectible-Editions.jpg 353w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Persuasion-Barnes-Noble-Collectible-Editions-189x300.jpg 189w" sizes="(max-width: 353px) 100vw, 353px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">source: pinterest</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The story concerns Anne Elliot, an Englishwoman of 27 years, whose family moves to lower their expenses and reduce their debt by renting their home to an Admiral and his wife. The wife&#8217;s brother, Captain Frederick Wentworth, was engaged to Anne in 1806, but the engagement was broken when Anne was persuaded by her friends and family to end their relationship. Anne and Captain Wentworth, both single and unattached, meet again after a seven-year separation, setting the scene for many humorous encounters as well as a second, well-considered chance at love and marriage for Anne.</p>



<p>The novel was well-received in the early 19th century, but its greater fame came later in the century and continued into the 20th and 21st centuries. Much scholarly debate on Austen&#8217;s work has since been published. Anne Elliot is noteworthy among Austen&#8217;s heroines for her relative maturity. As&nbsp;<em>Persuasion</em>&nbsp;was Austen&#8217;s last completed work, it is accepted as her most maturely written novel, showing a refinement of literary conception indicative of a woman approaching 40 years of age. Her use of&nbsp;free indirect speech&nbsp;in narrative was in full evidence by 1816.</p>



<p><em>Persuasion</em>&nbsp;has been the subject of several adaptations, including four made-for-television adaptations, theatre productions, radio broadcasts, and other literary works.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EMMA</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Novel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Emma&#160;is a novel about youthful&#160;hubris&#160;and romantic misunderstandings, written by&#160;Jane Austen. It is set in the fictional country village of Highbury and the surrounding estates of Hartfield, Randalls and Donwell Abbey, and involves the relationships among people from a small number of families.&#160;The novel was first published in December 1815, with its title page listing a publication date of 1816. As in her other novels, Austen explores the concerns and difficulties of genteel women living in&#160;Georgian–Regency&#160;England.&#160;Emma&#160;is a&#160;comedy of manners. Before she began the novel, Austen wrote, &#8220;I am going to take a heroine whom no one but myself will much like.&#8221;&#160;In the first sentence, she introduces the title character as &#8220;Emma Woodhouse, handsome, clever, and rich, with a comfortable home and a happy disposition&#8230; had lived nearly twenty-one years in the world with very little to distress or vex her.&#8221;&#160;Emma is spoiled, headstrong, and self-satisfied; she greatly overestimates her own matchmaking abilities; she is blind to the dangers of meddling in other people&#8217;s lives; and her imagination and perceptions often lead her astray. Emma, written after Austen&#8217;s move to&#160;Chawton, was her last novel to be published during her lifetime,&#160;while&#160;Persuasion, the last complete novel Austen wrote, was published posthumously.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Emma</strong></em>&nbsp;is a novel about youthful&nbsp;hubris&nbsp;and romantic misunderstandings, written by&nbsp;Jane Austen. It is set in the fictional country village of Highbury and the surrounding estates of Hartfield, Randalls and Donwell Abbey, and involves the relationships among people from a small number of families.&nbsp;The novel was first published in December 1815, with its title page listing a publication date of 1816. As in her other novels, Austen explores the concerns and difficulties of genteel women living in&nbsp;Georgian–Regency&nbsp;England.&nbsp;<em>Emma</em>&nbsp;is a&nbsp;comedy of manners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="434" height="600" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma-by-Jane-Austen.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-79" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma-by-Jane-Austen.jpg 434w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma-by-Jane-Austen-217x300.jpg 217w" sizes="(max-width: 434px) 100vw, 434px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">source: pinterest</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Before she began the novel, Austen wrote, &#8220;I am going to take a heroine whom no one but myself will much like.&#8221;&nbsp;In the first sentence, she introduces the title character as &#8220;Emma Woodhouse, handsome, clever, and rich, with a comfortable home and a happy disposition&#8230; had lived nearly twenty-one years in the world with very little to distress or vex her.&#8221;&nbsp;Emma is spoiled, headstrong, and self-satisfied; she greatly overestimates her own matchmaking abilities; she is blind to the dangers of meddling in other people&#8217;s lives; and her imagination and perceptions often lead her astray.</p>



<p><em>Emma</em>, written after Austen&#8217;s move to&nbsp;Chawton, was her last novel to be published during her lifetime,&nbsp;while&nbsp;<em>Persuasion</em>, the last complete novel Austen wrote, was published posthumously.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pride &#038; Prejudice</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-and-prejudice/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-and-prejudice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Novel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=71</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pride and Prejudice&#160;is an 1813&#160;novel of manners&#160;by&#160;Jane Austen. The novel follows the character development of&#160;Elizabeth Bennet, the dynamic&#160;protagonist&#160;of the book who learns about the repercussions of hasty judgments and comes to appreciate the difference between superficial goodness and actual goodness. Mr. Bennet, owner of the Longbourn estate in&#160;Hertfordshire, has five daughters, but his property is&#160;entailed&#160;and can only be passed to a male heir. His wife also lacks an inheritance, so his family faces becoming poor upon his death. Thus, it is imperative that at least one of the daughters marries well to support the others, which is a motivation that drives the plot. Pride and Prejudice&#160;has consistently appeared near the top of lists of &#8220;most-loved books&#8221; among literary scholars and the reading public. It has become one of the most popular novels in English literature, with over 20 million copies sold, and has inspired many derivatives in modern literature.&#160;For more than a century, dramatic adaptations, reprints, unofficial sequels, films, and TV versions of&#160;Pride and Prejudice&#160;have portrayed the memorable characters and themes of the novel, reaching mass audiences.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Pride and Prejudice</strong></em>&nbsp;is an 1813&nbsp;novel of manners&nbsp;by&nbsp;Jane Austen. The novel follows the character development of&nbsp;Elizabeth Bennet, the dynamic&nbsp;protagonist&nbsp;of the book who learns about the repercussions of hasty judgments and comes to appreciate the difference between superficial goodness and actual goodness.</p>



<p>Mr. Bennet, owner of the Longbourn estate in&nbsp;Hertfordshire, has five daughters, but his property is&nbsp;entailed&nbsp;and can only be passed to a male heir. His wife also lacks an inheritance, so his family faces becoming poor upon his death. Thus, it is imperative that at least one of the daughters marries well to support the others, which is a motivation that drives the plot.</p>



<p><em>Pride and Prejudice</em>&nbsp;has consistently appeared near the top of lists of &#8220;most-loved books&#8221; among literary scholars and the reading public. It has become one of the most popular novels in English literature, with over 20 million copies sold, and has inspired many derivatives in modern literature.&nbsp;For more than a century, dramatic adaptations, reprints, unofficial sequels, films, and TV versions of&nbsp;<em>Pride and Prejudice</em>&nbsp;have portrayed the memorable characters and themes of the novel, reaching mass audiences.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="520" height="742" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Book-Review_-_Pride-and-Prejudice_-by-Jane-Austen-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-73" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Book-Review_-_Pride-and-Prejudice_-by-Jane-Austen-1.png 520w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Book-Review_-_Pride-and-Prejudice_-by-Jane-Austen-1-210x300.png 210w" sizes="(max-width: 520px) 100vw, 520px" /></figure></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-and-prejudice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
