<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Novel &#8211; Jane Austen Core</title>
	<atom:link href="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/category/novel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore</link>
	<description>The Vintage Library</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 01:50:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/cropped-6538dbc9-22f4-47e1-b42e-f73d66293da8-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Novel &#8211; Jane Austen Core</title>
	<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Persuasion</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Novel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=84</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Persuasion&#160;is the last novel completed by&#160;Jane Austen. It was published on December 20, 1817, along with&#160;Northanger Abbey, six months after her death, although the title page is dated 1818. The story concerns Anne Elliot, an Englishwoman of 27 years, whose family moves to lower their expenses and reduce their debt by renting their home to an Admiral and his wife. The wife&#8217;s brother, Captain Frederick Wentworth, was engaged to Anne in 1806, but the engagement was broken when Anne was persuaded by her friends and family to end their relationship. Anne and Captain Wentworth, both single and unattached, meet again after a seven-year separation, setting the scene for many humorous encounters as well as a second, well-considered chance at love and marriage for Anne. The novel was well-received in the early 19th century, but its greater fame came later in the century and continued into the 20th and 21st centuries. Much scholarly debate on Austen&#8217;s work has since been published. Anne Elliot is noteworthy among Austen&#8217;s heroines for her relative maturity. As&#160;Persuasion&#160;was Austen&#8217;s last completed work, it is accepted as her most maturely written novel, showing a refinement of literary conception indicative of a woman approaching 40 years of age. Her use of&#160;free indirect speech&#160;in narrative was in full evidence by 1816. Persuasion&#160;has been the subject of several adaptations, including four made-for-television adaptations, theatre productions, radio broadcasts, and other literary works.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Persuasion</strong></em>&nbsp;is the last novel completed by&nbsp;Jane Austen. It was published on December 20, 1817, along with&nbsp;<em>Northanger Abbey</em>, six months after her death, although the title page is dated 1818.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="353" height="561" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Persuasion-Barnes-Noble-Collectible-Editions.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-85" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Persuasion-Barnes-Noble-Collectible-Editions.jpg 353w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Persuasion-Barnes-Noble-Collectible-Editions-189x300.jpg 189w" sizes="(max-width: 353px) 100vw, 353px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">source: pinterest</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The story concerns Anne Elliot, an Englishwoman of 27 years, whose family moves to lower their expenses and reduce their debt by renting their home to an Admiral and his wife. The wife&#8217;s brother, Captain Frederick Wentworth, was engaged to Anne in 1806, but the engagement was broken when Anne was persuaded by her friends and family to end their relationship. Anne and Captain Wentworth, both single and unattached, meet again after a seven-year separation, setting the scene for many humorous encounters as well as a second, well-considered chance at love and marriage for Anne.</p>



<p>The novel was well-received in the early 19th century, but its greater fame came later in the century and continued into the 20th and 21st centuries. Much scholarly debate on Austen&#8217;s work has since been published. Anne Elliot is noteworthy among Austen&#8217;s heroines for her relative maturity. As&nbsp;<em>Persuasion</em>&nbsp;was Austen&#8217;s last completed work, it is accepted as her most maturely written novel, showing a refinement of literary conception indicative of a woman approaching 40 years of age. Her use of&nbsp;free indirect speech&nbsp;in narrative was in full evidence by 1816.</p>



<p><em>Persuasion</em>&nbsp;has been the subject of several adaptations, including four made-for-television adaptations, theatre productions, radio broadcasts, and other literary works.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/persuasion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EMMA</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Novel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Emma&#160;is a novel about youthful&#160;hubris&#160;and romantic misunderstandings, written by&#160;Jane Austen. It is set in the fictional country village of Highbury and the surrounding estates of Hartfield, Randalls and Donwell Abbey, and involves the relationships among people from a small number of families.&#160;The novel was first published in December 1815, with its title page listing a publication date of 1816. As in her other novels, Austen explores the concerns and difficulties of genteel women living in&#160;Georgian–Regency&#160;England.&#160;Emma&#160;is a&#160;comedy of manners. Before she began the novel, Austen wrote, &#8220;I am going to take a heroine whom no one but myself will much like.&#8221;&#160;In the first sentence, she introduces the title character as &#8220;Emma Woodhouse, handsome, clever, and rich, with a comfortable home and a happy disposition&#8230; had lived nearly twenty-one years in the world with very little to distress or vex her.&#8221;&#160;Emma is spoiled, headstrong, and self-satisfied; she greatly overestimates her own matchmaking abilities; she is blind to the dangers of meddling in other people&#8217;s lives; and her imagination and perceptions often lead her astray. Emma, written after Austen&#8217;s move to&#160;Chawton, was her last novel to be published during her lifetime,&#160;while&#160;Persuasion, the last complete novel Austen wrote, was published posthumously.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Emma</strong></em>&nbsp;is a novel about youthful&nbsp;hubris&nbsp;and romantic misunderstandings, written by&nbsp;Jane Austen. It is set in the fictional country village of Highbury and the surrounding estates of Hartfield, Randalls and Donwell Abbey, and involves the relationships among people from a small number of families.&nbsp;The novel was first published in December 1815, with its title page listing a publication date of 1816. As in her other novels, Austen explores the concerns and difficulties of genteel women living in&nbsp;Georgian–Regency&nbsp;England.&nbsp;<em>Emma</em>&nbsp;is a&nbsp;comedy of manners.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="434" height="600" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma-by-Jane-Austen.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-79" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma-by-Jane-Austen.jpg 434w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Emma-by-Jane-Austen-217x300.jpg 217w" sizes="(max-width: 434px) 100vw, 434px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">source: pinterest</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Before she began the novel, Austen wrote, &#8220;I am going to take a heroine whom no one but myself will much like.&#8221;&nbsp;In the first sentence, she introduces the title character as &#8220;Emma Woodhouse, handsome, clever, and rich, with a comfortable home and a happy disposition&#8230; had lived nearly twenty-one years in the world with very little to distress or vex her.&#8221;&nbsp;Emma is spoiled, headstrong, and self-satisfied; she greatly overestimates her own matchmaking abilities; she is blind to the dangers of meddling in other people&#8217;s lives; and her imagination and perceptions often lead her astray.</p>



<p><em>Emma</em>, written after Austen&#8217;s move to&nbsp;Chawton, was her last novel to be published during her lifetime,&nbsp;while&nbsp;<em>Persuasion</em>, the last complete novel Austen wrote, was published posthumously.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/emma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pride &#038; Prejudice</title>
		<link>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-and-prejudice/</link>
					<comments>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-and-prejudice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Novel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/?p=71</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pride and Prejudice&#160;is an 1813&#160;novel of manners&#160;by&#160;Jane Austen. The novel follows the character development of&#160;Elizabeth Bennet, the dynamic&#160;protagonist&#160;of the book who learns about the repercussions of hasty judgments and comes to appreciate the difference between superficial goodness and actual goodness. Mr. Bennet, owner of the Longbourn estate in&#160;Hertfordshire, has five daughters, but his property is&#160;entailed&#160;and can only be passed to a male heir. His wife also lacks an inheritance, so his family faces becoming poor upon his death. Thus, it is imperative that at least one of the daughters marries well to support the others, which is a motivation that drives the plot. Pride and Prejudice&#160;has consistently appeared near the top of lists of &#8220;most-loved books&#8221; among literary scholars and the reading public. It has become one of the most popular novels in English literature, with over 20 million copies sold, and has inspired many derivatives in modern literature.&#160;For more than a century, dramatic adaptations, reprints, unofficial sequels, films, and TV versions of&#160;Pride and Prejudice&#160;have portrayed the memorable characters and themes of the novel, reaching mass audiences.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>Pride and Prejudice</strong></em>&nbsp;is an 1813&nbsp;novel of manners&nbsp;by&nbsp;Jane Austen. The novel follows the character development of&nbsp;Elizabeth Bennet, the dynamic&nbsp;protagonist&nbsp;of the book who learns about the repercussions of hasty judgments and comes to appreciate the difference between superficial goodness and actual goodness.</p>



<p>Mr. Bennet, owner of the Longbourn estate in&nbsp;Hertfordshire, has five daughters, but his property is&nbsp;entailed&nbsp;and can only be passed to a male heir. His wife also lacks an inheritance, so his family faces becoming poor upon his death. Thus, it is imperative that at least one of the daughters marries well to support the others, which is a motivation that drives the plot.</p>



<p><em>Pride and Prejudice</em>&nbsp;has consistently appeared near the top of lists of &#8220;most-loved books&#8221; among literary scholars and the reading public. It has become one of the most popular novels in English literature, with over 20 million copies sold, and has inspired many derivatives in modern literature.&nbsp;For more than a century, dramatic adaptations, reprints, unofficial sequels, films, and TV versions of&nbsp;<em>Pride and Prejudice</em>&nbsp;have portrayed the memorable characters and themes of the novel, reaching mass audiences.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="520" height="742" src="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Book-Review_-_Pride-and-Prejudice_-by-Jane-Austen-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-73" srcset="https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Book-Review_-_Pride-and-Prejudice_-by-Jane-Austen-1.png 520w, https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Book-Review_-_Pride-and-Prejudice_-by-Jane-Austen-1-210x300.png 210w" sizes="(max-width: 520px) 100vw, 520px" /></figure></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://libraryphile.github.io/austencore/index.php/2022/12/22/pride-and-prejudice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
